常軌を逸した狂気のゲーム
The extraordinary game
of insanity.
３種類 10枚のカードを使って
行われるゲーム｢Ｅカード｣
A game using ten cards of
three different types, E-Card.
Win and get great fortune.
勝てば大金を手に
負ければ その代償として
If he loses, he will lose his sense
of hearing in his left ear.
左耳の聴力を失う
カイジは初戦 ２戦と
連続で勝ちを拾い
Kaiji won two games in a row
and gained two million!
200万を得る
ふっふっ… 感じる 感じる
I can finally feel it!
Finally the feeling is
passed on to me...
ようやく気配が届いてきた
カイジ君の心の波動が
The vibrations of your heart,
今 少しずつ　ふっふっふっ…
little by little...
では ３戦目だ
Now, let's proceed
to the third match.
Adversity
何をわけの分からないことを
What exactly is he talking about?
とんだ負け惜しみ
He is such a sore loser.
It's nothing but a bluff!
こけおどしに決まってる
オープン
Open!
Just like in the first two rounds,
both players chose...
１～２戦目と同じく
１枚目は両者ともに市民を選択
...Citizen as their first card.
この３戦目の後 今度は俺が奴隷側
勝ちにくくなる
After this third round,  I'll have
to play on the Slave side.
It will be harder to win.
もうひとつ ここで勝っておきたい
I want to win again.
どうする？もう１回
ここで皇帝を通しに行くか？
What should I do?
Shall I use the Emperor
one more time?
まさか３回連続とは思うまい
He wouldn't expect
three Emperors in a row.
I can finally feel it,
the vibrations of your heart.
感じる 感じる
心の波動
For sure, that was
definitely just a bluff!
こけおどしだ あんなもの
ハッタリなんだ
感じる 感じる
I can finally feel it!
Darn it!
くそっ
Come on! Slave!
来い　奴隷
奴隷で自爆しろ
Darn it! Use the Slave
and blow yourself up!
勝負は初めて３枚目に突入
They played the third card
for the first time.
どうする？
もう一度 市民で行くか？
What should I do?
Play the Citizen once more?
いや… ここで市民を選択して
また引き分けになると
No...
If Citizen is used here,
the game will be a draw.
残り２枚　勝率は５分５分
The probability
will then be 50-50.
I'll settle this here!
ここで勝負だ
Come on! Citizen!
来い　市民！
皇帝でねじ伏せてやる
I'll crush you with the Emperor!
来い　来い　市民
Come on! Citizen!
そんなに強く念じられては
丸聞こえだ
Don't stress yourself
by thinking too much.
はっきりと聞こえてきたぞ
I can hear you clearly.
"Come on, Citizen!" you said.
｢来い 市民！｣ とな
What?
つまりカイジ君のカードは皇帝
Which means, your card is...
Emperor!
バカな　こいつ 本当に
俺の思ってたことを…
No way!
Could he really hear
what I was thinking?
Don't tell me he's psychic?
まさか読心術？
ふふふ… さあ オープンしたまえ
Now, show me your card.
カイジ　初めての敗北
Kaiji loses for the first time.
では参ろうか さっそく
Now, let's get started.
10mm.
10ミリだ
Drill, drill, drill...
The sound is
inaudible from here,
外に漏れる音はわずか
but for you,
it's tearing you up inside.
しばらくは残響で
顔も上げられまい
You won't be able to
lift your head up with that...
...deafening sound
reverberating in your ears.
Tonegawa.
利根川　ほどほどにな
Bring it down a notch.
相手の混乱を誘う話術も面白いが
Although it's interesting to
wear your opponent down,
度が過ぎて
カイジ君が恐れるあまり
Kaiji might lose
all his will to fight...
...if you push him
over the edge.
戦意喪失しては興を失う
Director, don't worry.
会長　ご安心を
Kaiji's not the way he seems.
こう見えてカイジ君は
なかなかの つわものでして
I'm certain that he
can see right through this.
この程度のことは
あっさりと見破ってくれます
See right through it?
見破る？話術？
俺を混乱させるだと？
To confuse me?
ハメやがったな 利根川
You tricked me, Tonegawa!
お前は俺の心が
読めたわけじゃない
You can't read my mind at all!
あれは俺の考えを言い当てたふり
カマをかけたんだ
You were just pretending
to be able to!
It was just a trick!
ほう…
ああいう場合
It's natural to want your
opponent to play a certain card.
相手の出してほしいカードを
念じるのは当たり前だ
俺が念じるカードは
市民か奴隷のどちらか
The card I was hoping
has a 50% chance...
...of being either
a Citizen or Slave!
確率は50パーセント
"Come on", is just a
commonly used phrase!
｢来い｣という呼びかけも
言ってみりゃ常套句
そんなに強く念じられては
丸聞こえだ
Don't stress yourself up
by thinking too much.
はっきりと聞こえてきたぞ
I can hear you clearly.
"Come on, Citizen!" you said.
｢来い 市民！｣ とな
俺の動揺を見て
図星と分かったところで
You figured out my card when
you saw that I was agitated.
つまりカイジ君のカードは皇帝
Which means, your card is...
Emperor!
自分のカードを選択した
Then you chose your card!
本当に俺の心が読めてたなら
If you're truly psychic,
then show your card before mine!
最初に自分のカードを出せば
いいはずだ
さすがはカイジ君
As I expected of Kaiji.
だが50点だ
But you are only half right.
"Please", "I  beg of you"...
｢お願い｣｢頼む｣
"Come here", "Come on".
｢来てくれ｣｢来い｣
Indeed, these are
commonly used phrases...
確かにあの状況で
相手に出してほしいカードを
念じる時に使う言葉としては
一般的だ
...in hoping that your opponent
plays the card you want.
And when you're winning
for 90% of the time,
ましてや連勝している
あの場面では
you are more likely
to say "Come on".
最も積極的な言葉 ｢来い｣を使う
That was exactly
what you were thinking.
その点は君の想像どおりだ
You!
貴様！
ただ…
However...
You were wrong to say that
I guessed it was a Citizen card.
カードを市民と言い当てた点は
まるでダメだ
What?
何？
君は私が５割の確率で
You assumed that I
chose the card at random.
適当に選んだと
考えているようだが
そんな安っぽいもんじゃない
But it's not that simple.
私は本当に感じられるんだ
I can really feel it.
人の心の震え どのカードを
出そうとしているのか
The beating of hearts...
...and which card
they have chosen.
ふざけるな　じゃあ何か？
That's a lie!
What then? Can you see
right through my soul?
心が透けて見えるとでも
言うのか？
Are you a mind reader?
お前は超能力者だと
Of course,
I'm not a mind reader.
もちろん私は
超能力者などではない
だが それに近いことはできる
何だと？
But I can do something like that.
What did you say?!
It's due to experience.
経験によってな
私はそれこそ
10年20年と見続けてきた
In the past 20 years,
I have witnessed...
...many deaths
caused by gambling.
生き死にに関わる人間の姿をな
People struggling with debts
and living at their wits end.
人生のどん詰まりで
彼らが何を考え 何を望むか
I've seen what these people
hope and wish for...
その心の揺れが 体のどの部分に
反応として現れるかを見てきた
...and the constant
trembling of their hearts.
だから このＥカードも
That's why
in this game of E-Card,
１～２回見ただけで
相手がどのタイプに属する人間か
I have an uncanny ability
to judge a player...
おおよそ見当がついてしまう
...after a round or two.
You are no exception.
君も例外ではない
その性質や癖
With your temperament
and habits,
今やすでに この手の中
you're like an open book.
残りの９戦
君はこの中でもがくだけ
In the remaining nine rounds,
you will surely lose.
Give me a break!
いい加減にしろ　１勝しただけで
得意げにハッタリかましやがって
Don't be so cocky!
You've only won one game!
You'll know when we play.
やれば分かる
Now it's your turn to
play the Slave side.
今度は君が奴隷側だ
俺の考えが読めるだと？
He read my thoughts!
But that's impossible!
そんなこと…
What's the problem?
どうした？
お前のくだらないハッタリで
ケチがついた
Your stupid trick
ruined my mood.
顔でも洗ってくる
I'm going to wash my face.
人の心を読むなんて
できっこねえ
There's no way
he can read minds!
No way!
できっこねえんだ
できっこねえ
どうだった？
Well?
カードに印など
ついてなかったろう？
There are no marks
on the cards, right?
そんなこと やりはせんよ
I wouldn't do such a thing.
そんなことをすれば バレた時に
逆に利用されかねない
I doubt I'd ever stoop so low
just to win a game.
To us, this game is purely
for recreation's sake.
第一 君はともかく
我々にしてみれば
今回のゲームは遊び
I'm just enjoying the
psychological battle with you.
純粋にカイジ君との心理戦を
楽しもうとしているだけ
印など無用だ
There's no need to mark them.
むしろ君が印をつけていないか…
どうぞ
Rather, we should be
keeping an eye on you.
Sir.
こちらが警戒しなければ
いけないくらいだ
Just to be safe.
では再開するとしよう
Let's get on with the game.
さて ベットは？
Now, what's your bet?
変わらず10か？
10 as usual?
2000万に届くためには そう簡単に
距離は減らせないだろうからな
To get 20 million, you can't
reduce the amount too much.
Darn you!
ふざけろ
Maybe I'll win three in a row.
３連勝したのなら ともかく
今度は勝ちの薄い奴隷側で
10ミリも張れるわけない
This time, I'm playing on the
Slave side. I won't bet 10mm!
ほう
それは すばらしい
何だと？
That's wonderful.
What?
さっき会長と次にカイジ君が
We were just discussing
how much you would wager.
どれだけ張ってくるか
という話になってね
That's right.
We had an agreement.
互いに意見が一致したところだ
ここで10張るようなヤツは
話にならんとな
Anyone who bets 10
at this point is worthless.
そんなやからは
ただの怖いもの知らず
Only fools would bet
so foolishly and carelessly.
引くべきところは引く
それが我々の言うところの
つわものだ
You are indeed as good
as we said.
では いくら張る？
So what will your wager be?
２だ
2.
10から２か
From 10 to 2?
Shut up!
黙れ　８や５は張れとでも
言いたいんだろうが 今は…
You wanted me to place
a higher bet, but now...
逆だ
It's opposite!
誠のつわものならば
ここは１まで落とす
At this stage, a real fighter
would reduce it to 1.
勝算もなく
流れが相手に傾いている今
With no guarantee of winning and
the tide in the opponent's hand,
you should place
your bet at 1.
張りは限界まで落とすべき
なのに君は２を張るという
Despite that, you bet 2.
この余分な１は
カイジ君の心のぜい肉
Kaiji, the additional 1mm
is merely your foolish pride.
見えというものだ
死ぬぞ　その見えが
あとあとカイジ君の首を絞める
You will falter.
That pride of yours will
be your downfall.
どうする？今なら変更を認めよう
What will you do?
You're still allowed
to make changes.
男がいったん口にした張りを
Once a man places his bet,
the decision is final!
そうヒョイヒョイ変えられるか
ほっとけ
Let it be!
- Drill, drill, drill...
- I see.
そうか　別にこちらはかまわんよ
It makes no difference to us.
Yes, Sir.
カイジ　奴隷側となっての４戦目
The fourth game, with
Kaiji on the Slave side...
皇帝側の利根川に続いて
カードの選択
...and Tonegawa
on the Emperor side.
He chooses his card.
ここで勝てば流れを変えられる
If he wins here,
the flow will change.
But there's a thought
that Kaiji can't shake off.
だが カイジの心には
拭いきれない考えが生じている
ハッタリだと分かっていながらも
ひょっとすると
Even if he knows it's a bluff,
there might be a chance...
本当に心を
見抜かれているのではないかと
...that his mind is
indeed being read.
いや そう考えさせることが
ヤツの手
No, it's just a trick he's using.
この呪縛 解かなきゃダメだ
I must break out of this trap!
そのためには勝つしかない
To do that, I have to win!
If I win this round,
Tonegawa's tactics will fail.
俺が勝てば 利根川の
あの大仰な言葉も すべてごたく
魔法は解ける
待てよ　てことは
負けられないのは
Wait a minute.
Tonegawa has much more
to lose than I do.
俺よりむしろ利根川
有利なはずの皇帝で
ましてや あの会長とやらの前で
With Emperor
as the advantage...
...and losing to me
in front of the Director,
俺みたいな小物相手に
負けるなんて醜態
許されるはずがない
they'd never forgive him!
利根川は今
俺以上に勝ちたいはずなんだ
Tonegawa is under more
pressure to win than I am.
とすれば ヤツのカードは何だ？
皇帝か？
Which card is he holding?
Emperor?
いや 違う
ヤツは今 あおることで
No, that's not right.
He is now trying
to read my mind.
俺を一種の興奮状態に導き
１枚目から奴隷で
勝負を仕掛ける状況を作ったんだ
Dealing a Slave card as your
first hand would be risking it all.
なら その危険な１枚目に
皇帝を出してくるはずはない
Even so, he would not place
Emperor as his very first card.
１枚目はリスクを避けて… 市民
The first card would be
to avoid risk.
Citizen!
オープン
Open!
思ったとおり　もし今
皇帝を出していたら利根川の勝ち
As I expected!
If Tonegawa placed an
Emperor then, he'd win.
それが できなかった
ということは
This shows that he can't
predict the cards at all.
カードを読み切ってなど
いないということ
つまり 貴様お得意の話術
In other words,
all that talk was just a lie!
ハッタリ　勝機はある
There is a winning chance!
２枚目のカードはカイジから
The second card
starts with Kaiji.
ここが最初のヤマ
This is the first obstacle.
For either side, it is difficult
to deal a major card...
基本的に皇帝側も奴隷側も
自分が先にカードを提出する時
勝敗の鍵となる皇帝や奴隷は
出しにくい
...like Emperor or Slave
at this point.
先にカードを決した側には
心理的な圧迫がある
For the one who has to go first,
the pressure mounts.
顔色からカードを
察知されることもありうる
From his expression,
it'd possible to predict his card.
その状況下で鍵となるカードを
出すことは避ける
In this situation, one has to
avoid playing the decisive card.
特に皇帝側は
市民だけ出していれば
On the Emperor side,
if you play the Citizen...
...and the opponent
plays a Slave,
相手が奴隷を出して
自滅する確率が高く
無理に勝負に行く必要はない
chances are that
he would be defeated.
先出しの１枚目と３枚目は
皇帝を出したくない
He would avoid
dealing the Emperor...
...for the first and third cards.
ってことは 逆に考えれば…
In other words...
こんな序盤でもう長考か？
What's the matter?
I see that someone is
thinking way too much.
下手な考え 何とやら
Thinking too much might
just be your downfall.
これでは先が思いやられるな
ここから先の修羅場が
And the gates of doom await.
さて カイジ君が
じっくり考えたカード
The card that you pondered
so carefully over...
何が来たか
What would it be?
これは難しいぞ
This is pretty hard.
２枚目だ　利根川が
皇帝を通すとしたら２枚目だ
The second card!
If Tonegawa wants
to deal the Emperor,
it'd be the second card!
皇帝側からすれば
後出しの２枚目と４枚目
From the Emperor side,
one must place it on
the second or fourth card.
このどちらかで
勝負のカードを出す
This way,
one can aim for victory.
だが４枚目で勝負となると
勝率は５割
But by the fourth card,
chances would be 50-50.
それは避けたいはずだ
He ought to
want to avoid that.
ならば ２枚目…
２枚目に出してくるはずだ
In other words...
The second card!
The second card has to be it!
難しいが まあ… これか
It might be hard, but...
This is it.
市民！
Citizen?
たわいもない　こちらが
仕掛けずとも自ら転んでくれる
How foolish.
I don't have to do anything
and yet you've faltered.
カイジ君　援軍だ
援軍？
Kaiji, you have reinforcements.
Reinforcements?
何の力にもならぬ
クズのような援軍だがな
However, reinforcements with
no value or use whatsoever.
さて 続けようか
Now, shall we continue?
どうしたらいい？
どう戦ったらいいんだ
What should I do?
How should I fight this?
行き詰まったカイジ
突破口を開く策
Kaiji is now in a dilemma!
Where would he find the solution
to lead him to victory?
勝負するための方向性 羅針盤を
彼は必要としていた
He needs a guide
to show him the way.
このままでは あまりにも無策
At this rate,
he's simply aimless.
ただ寄る辺なく
勝負という海原を漂うだけ
He is just drifting along
with no clue of his direction.
What is your next bet, Kaiji?
カイジ君　次のベットは？
心のぜい肉…
My foolish pride...
２だ
いいのか 本当に２で？
2.
Are you sure that's your bet?
勝ちゃいいんだろ 勝ちゃ　２だ
It doesn't matter
as long as I win! My bet is 2!
とんだ頑固もんだ
What a stubborn fellow.
人が親切心でしている忠告も
素直に聞けんとはな
To think that you're
refusing my good advice.
ふざけるな　その口車に乗って
Quit messing around!
I'll never heed your words
and fall into your trap!
これ以上 貴様のペースに
巻き込まれてたまるか
I will make my own decisions.
自分の心の主導権は自分で持つ
なら２だ　意地を張ってでも
That's why I'll bet 2,
even if it's out of pride!
５戦目
皇帝の利根川がカードを選択
For the fifth game,
Tonegawa chooses his card first.
そして繰り返される同じ思考
同じ理論
It's the same strategy
and mentality.
皇帝側では 先出しの１枚で
まず勝負には来ない
The Emperor won't be
placed as the first card.
なら 市民
It has to be a Citizen.
待てよ　ヤツはさっきの勝負
Wait. In the last match,
絶対 来ると思った２枚目で
皇帝を出さなかった
he didn't deal Emperor for the
second card as I expected him to.
てことは…
In other words...
１度 考え出すと止まらない疑念
On starting to ponder,
the indecisiveness begins.
それは瞬く間に広がり
思考を迷走に導く
It leads to a labyrinth which
one may never escape.
カイジの心には今 重りがない
Kaiji's mind is
unstable right now.
勝つための思考を組み立てる
足がかり
He has no clue of any
strategy that would...
そこに勝負を委ねる
くさびのようなものがなく
...help him to win
this psychological battle.
ゆえに堂々巡りを繰り返す
And so he finds himself
in a precarious position...
無重力の空間を漂うように
頼りなく
...with his mind
wandering aimlessly.
奴隷か
Slave?
いや 出せねえ
No, I can't deal this!
オープン
Open!
面白かろう
Isn't this interesting?
今までにあったかね？
Have you
experienced this before?
これほど必死に人の心を…
真実を知ろうとしたことが
Wanting to know
the truth, that is.
これが本当の会話だ
This is a conversation.
本当の会話？
Conversation?
そう　このＥカードは
Right. E-Card is a game...
相手の心理 真実の心を
突き止めるゲーム
...to ascertain the opponent's
mind and his real intentions.
混じりっけなし
心と心の会話だ
A heart-to-heart conversation.
この会話の純粋さに比べれば
Compared to this, your daily
conversations with friends,
日常 友人との会話など
それが いかに真剣な
相談事であろうと
be it a serious discussion
or one in private,
打ち明け話であろうと
所詮はその場限りの
魂のない会話にすぎん
are transcient
and lack spirit.
だが 今はどうだ？
But what about this?
君は真剣に
私の心を測ろうとしている
You are trying hard
to figure me out,
むろん私もだ
and likewise on my part.
この圧倒的会話の濃度
The intensity
of this conversation...
日常では味わえまい
is not something you
can experience everyday.
しかも聴力を賭けているとなれば
必死にならざるを得ない
Furthermore, with your hearing
as a wager,
you have to beat me
no matter what.
Surely this is interesting, no?
面白くないはずがなかろう
震えるほどに味わえる
勝負の愉悦
Savour my impending victory!
Smell it!
醍醐味を
心と心の会話
A heart-to-heart conversation...
確かにこのＥカード
まったく読めなかった相手の心が
Indeed. In E-Card,
thoughts which are invisible...
数秒後 いともあっさり
明らかになる
...will become apparent.
The hidden thoughts
of the opponent...
隠されていた相手の本心…
真実が 何のカードを
出したかによって見えてくる
...will be revealed by
the cards that he deals.
Hesitation.
ちゅうちょ
躊躇　勇気　欲望　恐れ
Courage.
Desire.
Fear.
恐れ？
Fear?
そうだ　｢恐れ｣
I see. It's fear.
これだ！
That's it!
Like a brilliant flash, an idea
flashed through Kaiji's mind.
閃光のように
カイジの脳裏を走り抜けた思考
それは勝負に導く光明か
Is this the light that will
lead him to victory?
それとも破滅へ導く地獄の炎か
Or a hellfire that will
lead him to destruction?
ほんろう
次回｢翻弄｣
Next, Trifled.